<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<tt xmlns:tts="http://www.w3.org/2006/04/ttaf1#styling" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2006/04/ttaf1">
  <head/>
  <body>
    <div>
      <p begin="00:00:01.15" dur="00:00:03.22">This is not a work of fiction.</p>
      <p begin="00:00:04.38" dur="00:00:14.86">There is a place called "Island of Flowers"</p>
      <p begin="00:00:19.25" dur="00:00:06.81">We are in Belém Novo, municipality of Porto Alegre, state of Rio Grande do Sul, in southern Brazil,</p>
      <p begin="00:00:26.07" dur="00:00:08.51">more precisely at 30 degrees, 12 minutes and 30 seconds South, and 52 degrees, 11 minutes and 23 seconds West.</p>
      <p begin="00:00:34.58" dur="00:00:06.37">We are currently walking in a tomato plantation, and we can see ahead, standing, a human being, in this case, a japanese man.</p>
      <p begin="00:00:40.96" dur="00:00:06.55">The japanese are distinguished from other human beings by the shape of their eyes, their black hair, and by their characteristic names. </p>
      <p begin="00:00:47.51" dur="00:00:02.14">The japanese man in question is called</p>
      <p begin="00:00:49.65" dur="00:00:02.18">Suzuki.</p>
      <p begin="00:00:51.84" dur="00:00:04.55">Human beings are biped mammals, and distinguish themselves from other mammals, like whales,</p>
      <p begin="00:00:56.39" dur="00:00:07.41">or bipeds, like chickens, mainly by two characteristics: a highly developed telencephalon, and opposable thumbs.</p>
      <p begin="00:01:03.81" dur="00:00:05.70">The highly developed telencephalon allows human beings to store, associate, process and understand pieces of information.</p>
      <p begin="00:01:09.51" dur="00:00:07.71">The opposable thumb allows human beings a tweezer-like finger movement, which in turn allows for precise manipulation.</p>
      <p begin="00:01:17.23" dur="00:00:06.24">The highly developed telencephalon combined with the tweezer-like finger movement allowed human beings</p>
      <p begin="00:01:23.48" dur="00:00:05.28">to make innumerable improvements to their planet, including</p>
      <p begin="00:01:28.76" dur="00:00:02.66">growing tomatoes.</p>
      <p begin="00:01:31.42" dur="00:00:02.73">Tomatoes, unlike whales, chickens, and japanese people</p>
      <p begin="00:01:34.15" dur="00:00:02.00">is a vegetable.</p>
      <p begin="00:01:36.15" dur="00:00:05.09">Fruit of the tomato plant, tomatoes started being cultivated in the 1800s for its nutritional qualities.</p>
      <p begin="00:01:41.25" dur="00:00:03.90">Around 61 million tons of tomatoes are produces on Earth every year.</p>
      <p begin="00:01:45.15" dur="00:00:06.74">Mr Suzuki, despite working almost 12 hours daily, is responsible for a very small fraction of this production.</p>
      <p begin="00:01:51.90" dur="00:00:05.01">The main use of tomatoes is the feeding of humans.</p>
      <p begin="00:01:56.92" dur="00:00:06.32">Mr. Suzuki is a japanese man, and, therefore, a human being.  Despite this, Mr. Suzuki does not grow tomatoes with the intention to eat them. </p>
      <p begin="00:02:03.24" dur="00:00:05.66">Almost all tomatoes grown by Mr. Suzuki are delivered to the supermarket in exchange for money.</p>
      <p begin="00:02:08.91" dur="00:00:08.07">Money was most likely created as an initiative by Giges, King of Lidia, a great kingdom in Asia Minor, in the 7th centure before Christ.</p>
      <p begin="00:02:16.98" dur="00:00:02.92">Christ was a jew.</p>
      <p begin="00:02:19.91" dur="00:00:04.49">Jews have a highly developed telencephalon  and opposable thumbs.</p>
      <p begin="00:02:24.40" dur="00:00:04.11">They are, therefore, human beings.</p>
      <p begin="00:02:28.52" dur="00:00:03.64">Until the creation of money, the economy was based on the direct exchange of goods.</p>
      <p begin="00:02:32.16" dur="00:00:03.39">The difficulty of calculating the amount of tomatoes equivalent to a chicken</p>
      <p begin="00:02:35.56" dur="00:00:05.95">and the difficulty of the direct exchange of chickens for whales where the main motivations for the creation of money.</p>
      <p begin="00:02:41.51" dur="00:00:04.16">Starting in the thrid centure BC, any action of object made by human beings</p>
      <p begin="00:02:45.68" dur="00:00:05.00">fruit of the collaboration between the highly developed telencephalon  and the opposable thumbs, </p>
      <p begin="00:02:50.68" dur="00:00:07.11">as well as all living things, above and below ground -- tomatoes, chickens and whales -- can be exchanged for money.</p>
      <p begin="00:02:57.80" dur="00:00:04.35">To facilitate the exchange of tomatoes for money, human beings created supermarkets.</p>
      <p begin="00:03:02.15" dur="00:00:05.31">Ms. Anete is a Roman Apostolic Catholic biped mammal.</p>
      <p begin="00:03:07.47" dur="00:00:06.11">She has a highly developed telencephalon and opposable thumbs.  She is, therefore, a human being.</p>
      <p begin="00:03:13.59" dur="00:00:05.40">She came to this supermarket in order to exchange her money for tomatoes, amongst other things.</p>
      <p begin="00:03:19.00" dur="00:00:04.72">Ms. Anete obtained her money in exchange for the work she performs.</p>
      <p begin="00:03:23.72" dur="00:00:05.74">She uses her highly developed telencephalon and opposable thumbs to exchange perfumes for money.</p>
      <p begin="00:03:29.47" dur="00:00:07.08">Perfumes are liquids usually extracted from flowers, which make human beings smell more pleasantly than they would naturally.</p>
      <p begin="00:03:36.56" dur="00:00:06.42">Ms. Anete does not extract the perfumes. She exchanges them, at a factory, for a determined amount of money.</p>
      <p begin="00:03:42.98" dur="00:00:06.85">Once that is done, Ms. Anete walks from house to house, exchanging the perfumes for a slightly larger amount of money.</p>
      <p begin="00:03:49.84" dur="00:00:02.65">The difference between these two amount is called</p>
      <p begin="00:03:52.49" dur="00:00:01.75">profit.</p>
      <p begin="00:03:54.24" dur="00:00:04.55">Profit, which was once forbidden to Catholics, is today allowed for all human beings.</p>
      <p begin="00:03:58.79" dur="00:00:09.04">Ms. Anete's profit is small compared to the factory's profit, but it is enough to be exchanged for 1kg of tomatoes and 2 kg of meat -- in this case, the meat of a pig.</p>
      <p begin="00:04:07.84" dur="00:00:04.81">Pigs are mammals, like humans and whales, but quadrupeds.</p>
      <p begin="00:04:12.65" dur="00:00:05.48">They sever as food for the Japanese, the Catholics, and the remaining human beings -- with exception of the Jews.</p>
      <p begin="00:04:18.14" dur="00:00:07.52">The food that Ms. Anete exchanged for money, which she exchanged for perfumes extracted from flowers, will be consumed by her family during a single day.</p>
      <p begin="00:04:25.66" dur="00:00:05.25">A day is the time interval that it takes for the Earth to spin all the way around it's own axis.</p>
      <p begin="00:04:30.92" dur="00:00:03.51">Mid-day is lunch time.</p>
      <p begin="00:04:34.43" dur="00:00:08.78">A family is a community formed by a man and a woman, united in matrimony, and by the children born out of this union.</p>
      <p begin="00:04:43.22" dur="00:00:05.27">Some of the tomatoes Mr. Suzuki exchanged with the supermarket for money, and which were in turn exchanged for the money </p>
      <p begin="00:04:48.49" dur="00:00:06.34">that Ms. Anete obtained as profit in the exchange of perfumes extracted from flowers were transformed into sauce for the pork.</p>
      <p begin="00:04:54.84" dur="00:00:07.11">One of these tomatoes, which according to Ms. Anete was in no condition to become sauce, was thrown in the garbage.</p>
      <p begin="00:05:01.95" dur="00:00:07.14">Garbage is all that is produced by human beings, in a collaboration between the highly developed telencephalon and the opposable thumbs</p>
      <p begin="00:05:09.10" dur="00:00:04.80">and that, according to the opinion of some human being, is in no condition to become sauce.</p>
      <p begin="00:05:13.91" dur="00:00:05.93">In a city like Porto Alegre, inhabited by over a million human beings, produces around 500 tons of garbage daily.</p>
      <p begin="00:05:19.84" dur="00:00:04.28">Garbage attracts all kinds of germs and bacteria, which in turn cause disease.</p>
      <p begin="00:05:24.12" dur="00:00:03.83">Diseases seriously harm the normal functioning of human beings.</p>
      <p begin="00:05:27.95" dur="00:00:04.68">Even when it does cause disease, the apearence and aroma of garbage are extremely unpleasant.</p>
      <p begin="00:05:32.63" dur="00:00:09.17">This is why garbage is taken a determined places, very far, where it can freely soil, smell badly and attract disease.</p>
      <p begin="00:05:41.81" dur="00:00:04.18">In Porto Alegre, one of the places chosen for garbage to smell badly and attract disease is called</p>
      <p begin="00:05:46.00" dur="00:00:05.92">Island of Flowers</p>
      <p begin="00:05:51.92" dur="00:00:04.70">An island is a portion of land surrounded by water from all sides.</p>
      <p begin="00:05:56.62" dur="00:00:07.52">Water is a odorless, insipid and discoloured substance, formed by two hydrogen atoms and one oxygen atom.</p>
      <p begin="00:06:04.14" dur="00:00:04.62">Flowers are the reproductive organs of plants, usually scented and with bright colours.</p>
      <p begin="00:06:08.77" dur="00:00:06.32">Pleasantly smelling flowers can be turned into perfume, like the ones Ms Anete exchanged for money, which she in turn exchanged for tomatoes.</p>
      <p begin="00:06:15.09" dur="00:00:04.04">There are few flower at the Island of Flowers.</p>
      <p begin="00:06:19.14" dur="00:00:06.11">There is, however, a lot of garbage, and amongst it, the tomato Ms. Anete judged inadequate for the pork sauce.</p>
      <p begin="00:06:25.25" dur="00:00:04.66">There is also a lot of pigs.</p>
      <p begin="00:06:30.24" dur="00:00:04.26">The tomato Ms Anete judged inadequate for the pork she was serving as food for her family</p>
      <p begin="00:06:34.50" dur="00:00:05.14"> may turn out to be a great meal for a pig and its family, in the opinion of th epig.</p>
      <p begin="00:06:39.64" dur="00:00:07.34">It is important to remember Ms Anete has a highly developed telencephalon  and opposable thumbs, while pigs don't even have thumbs, let alone opposable ones.</p>
      <p begin="00:06:46.98" dur="00:00:04.28">Pigs have, however, an owner.</p>
      <p begin="00:06:51.27" dur="00:00:05.80">A pig's owner is a human being, with a highly developed telencephalon, opposable thumbs and money.</p>
      <p begin="00:06:57.07" dur="00:00:06.96">The pig's owner exchanged a small part of his money for a small plot of land in the Island of Flowers, thus becoming the owner of the plot.</p>
      <p begin="00:07:04.04" dur="00:00:04.00">A plot of land is a patch of land which has an owner and a fence.</p>
      <p begin="00:07:08.04" dur="00:00:06.53">This plot, where garbage is thrown, was fenced so that the pigs would not be able to go out, and so that human beings would not come in.</p>
      <p begin="00:07:19.00" dur="00:00:06.83">The employees of the pig's owner separate the organic matter which they think is fit for the pig's consumption from the garbage.</p>
      <p begin="00:07:25.83" dur="00:00:04.01">Organic matter is anything that was once living, in either animal or vegetable form.</p>
      <p begin="00:07:29.85" dur="00:00:03.50">Tomates, chickens, pigs, flowers and paper are all organic matter.</p>
      <p begin="00:07:33.35" dur="00:00:08.98">This piece of paper, for example, was used on a history test for high school students at the Nossa Senhora de Dores school,  and was given to the student Ana Luiza Nunes, a human being.</p>
      <p begin="00:07:42.34" dur="00:00:06.08">A history test is a test for the capacity of a human being's telencephalon  to remember data related to the study of history.</p>
      <p begin="00:07:48.42" dur="00:00:04.51">For example: who as Mem de Sá? What were the hereditary captaincies?</p>
      <p begin="00:07:53.31" dur="00:00:02.12">To remember is to live.</p>
      <p begin="00:07:55.43" dur="00:00:06.20">Some organic materials, like tomatoes and history tests, are given to pigs as food.</p>
      <p begin="00:08:01.64" dur="00:00:05.69">That which they consider inapropriate for the feeding of pigs, is used to feed women and children.</p>
      <p begin="00:08:08.46" dur="00:00:08.56">Women and children are human beings, with a highly developed telencephalon, opposable thumbs and no money.</p>
      <p begin="00:08:20.19" dur="00:00:03.50">They don't have an owner, and what is worse, they are many.</p>
      <p begin="00:08:23.69" dur="00:00:07.69">Being many, they are organized by the employees of the pig's owner into groups of 10, and they have the permission to go inside the fenced area.</p>
      <p begin="00:08:33.12" dur="00:00:08.90">Once inside the fenced area they can choose for themselves all the food the employees of the pig's owner judged innadequate for the pigs.</p>
      <p begin="00:08:42.72" dur="00:00:07.48">The employees stipulated that each group of 10 human beings has 5 minutes to stay within the fenced area</p>
      <p begin="00:08:50.20" dur="00:00:05.55">collecting organic matter, like tomatoes and history tests.</p>
      <p begin="00:08:55.75" dur="00:00:04.79">5 minutes are 300 seconds.</p>
      <p begin="00:09:00.55" dur="00:00:10.96">Since 1958, the second was defined as the equivalent of 9 billion, 192 million, 631 thousand and 770 cycles of radiation from a Cesium atom.</p>
      <p begin="00:09:11.52" dur="00:00:04.30">Cesium is a non-organic material found in the garbage in Goiânia.</p>
      <p begin="00:09:21.03" dur="00:00:05.00">The tomato, planted by Mr. Suzuki, exchanged for money at the supermarket,</p>
      <p begin="00:09:26.03" dur="00:00:07.80">exchanged for the money that Ms Anete exchanged for perfumes extracted from flowers, rejected for the pork sauce, thrown in the garbage,</p>
      <p begin="00:09:33.84" dur="00:00:04.55">rejected as food by the pigs, is now available for all the human beings at Island of Flowers.</p>
      <p begin="00:09:44.75" dur="00:00:04.50">What places the human beings at the Island of Flowers after the pigs in the priority for food choice</p>
      <p begin="00:09:49.26" dur="00:00:04.36">is the fact they have no money.</p>
      <p begin="00:09:59.72" dur="00:00:09.39">Human beings distinguish themselves from other animals by the highly developed telencephalon, opposable thumbs, and by being free.</p>
      <p begin="00:10:10.63" dur="00:00:04.21">Free is the state of a person with freedom.</p>
      <p begin="00:10:15.32" dur="00:00:03.71">Freedom is a word fed by human dreams, </p>
      <p begin="00:10:19.03" dur="00:00:02.38">that no one can explain,</p>
      <p begin="00:10:21.42" dur="00:00:03.23">and that nobody cannot understand.</p>
    </div>
  </body>
</tt>
